<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2021 Alexander Huntley <huntley.alexander@gmail.com> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.alexhuntley.Plots</id>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Plots</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">Grafikaĵoj</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Gráfico</name>
  <name xml:lang="fa">نمودارها</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Plots</name>
  <name xml:lang="hr">Grafikoni</name>
  <name xml:lang="hu">Ábrák</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Grafici</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Plots</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Grafer</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt_BR">Plots</name>
  <developer_name>Alex Huntley</developer_name>
  <summary>Simple graph plotting</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Simpla grafikaĵilo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Trazado sencillo de funciones</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fa">رسم نمودار ساده</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Traceur de fonction simple</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hr">Jednostavno crtanje grafikona</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hu">Egyszerű ábrákrajzolás</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Semplice disegnatore di grafici</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Eenvoudig grafieken plotten</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Enkel grafritning</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt_BR">Simples traçador de gráficos</summary>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      Plots makes it easy to visualise mathematical formulae. In addition to basic
      arithmetic operations, it supports trigonometric, hyperbolic, exponential and
      logarithmic functions, as well as arbitrary sums and products. It can display
      polar equations, and both implicit and explicit Cartesian equations.
    </p>
    <p>
      Plots is designed to integrate well with the GNOME desktop and takes advantage
      of modern hardware using OpenGL.
    </p>

    <p xml:lang="es">
      Gráfico facilita la visualización de fórmulas matemáticas. Además de las
      operaciones aritméticas básicas, admite funciones trigonométricas,
      hiperbólicas, exponenciales y logarítmicas, así como sumas y productos
      arbitrarios. Puede mostrar ecuaciones polares y ecuaciones cartesianas
      implícitas y explícitas.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="es">
      Gráfico está diseñado para integrarse bien con el escritorio GNOME y aprovecha
      el hardware moderno usando OpenGL.
    </p>

    <p xml:lang="fa">
      نمودارها، دیداری کردن فرمول‌های ریاضیاتی را ساده می‌کند.
      علاوه بر عملگرهای حسابیِ ساده، از توابع مثلثاتی، هذلولی، نمایی و لگاریتمی،
      و همچنین حاصل‌جمع‌ها و حاصل‌ضرب‌های سفارشی نیز پشتیبانی می‌کند.
      می‌تواند معادلات متقارن، و جفت معادلات ضمنی و صریح دکارتی را نمایش دهد.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="fa">
      نمودارها ساخته شده تا به‌خوبی با میزکار گنوم یک‌پارچه شود
      و با استفاده از OpenGL از سخت‌افزار نوین بهره ببرد.
    </p>

    <p xml:lang="fr">
      Plots permet de visualiser facilement des formules mathémathiques. En plus des
      opérations arithmétiques de base, il prend en charge les fonctions trigonométriques,
      hyperboliques, exponentielles et logarithmiques, ainsi que les sommes et produits
      arbitraires. Il peut afficher des equations polaires et des equations cartésiennes,
      implicites et explicites.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">
      Plots est conçu pour bien s'intégrer au bureau GNOME et exploite le matériel
      moderne en utilisant OpenGL.
    </p>

    <p xml:lang="hr">
      Program Grafikoni olakšava vizualizaciju matematičkih formula. Osim osnovnih
      aritmetičkih operacija, podržava trigonometrijske, hiperboličke, eksponencijalne i
      logaritamske funkcije, kao i proizvoljne zbrojeve i umnoške. Može prikazati polarne
      jednadžbe, te implicitne i eksplicitne kartezijanske jednadžbe.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="hr">
      Program Grafikoni izrađen je na način da se dobro integrira u GNOME okruženje te
      koristi prednosti modernog hardvera pomoću OpenGL-a.
    </p>

    <p xml:lang="hu">
      Ábrák megkönnyíti a matematikai képletek megjelenítését. Az alapvető számtani
      műveletek mellett támogatja a trigonometriai, hiperbolikus, exponenciális és
      logaritmikus függvényeket, valamint tetszőleges összegeket és szorzatokat.
      Poláris egyenleteket, valamint implicit és explicit derékszögű egyenleteket is
      megjeleníthet.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="hu">
      Tervezték az Ábrák, hogy jól illeszkedjen a GNOME asztalhoz, és kihasználja az
      OpenGL-t használó modern hardverek előnyeit.
    </p>

    <p xml:lang="it">
      Grafici rende facile la visulizzazione di formule matematiche. Assieme alle
      operazioni aritmetiche di base, ha il supporto delle funzioni trigonometriche,
      iperboliche, esponenziali e logaritmiche, oltre a somme e prodotti arbitrari.
      Può mostrare equazioni polari ed equazioni cartesiane esplicie e implicite.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="it">
      Grafici è stato progettato per integrarsi perfettamente con l'ambiente desktop GNOME e sfrutta
      l'uso di hardware moderno usando OpenGL.
    </p>

    <p xml:lang="nl">
      Plots maakt het eenvoudig om wiskundige formules te visualiseren. Naast de rekenkundige
      basisbewerkingen, ondersteunt het trigonometrische, hyperbolische, exponentiële en
      logaritmische functies, evenals willekeurige sommen en producten. Het kan polaire
      vergelijkingen en zowel impliciete als expliciete cartesiaanse vergelijkingen weergeven.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">
      Plots is ontworpen om goed te integreren met Gnome en maakt gebruik van van moderne hardware
      via OpenGL.
    </p>
    
    <p xml:lang="sv">
    Grafer gör det enkelt att visualisera matematiska formler. Förutom aritmetiken
       grundläggande operationer, det stödjer trigonometriska, hyperboliska, exponentiella och
       logaritmiska funktioner, samt godtyckliga summor och produkter. Det kan vara polärt
       ekvationer och visar både implicita och explicita kartesiska ekvationer.
    </p>
                 
    <p xml:lang="sv">
     Grafer är utformad för att integreras väl med Gnome och använder modern hårdvara
       genom OpenGL.
    </p>


    <p xml:lang="pt_BR">
      Plots permite a fácil visualização de fórmulas matemáticas. Além das operações
      aritméticas básicas, suporta funções trigonométricas, hiperbólicas, exponenciais
      e logarítmicas, bem como somas e produtos arbitrários. Também é capaz de exibir
      equações polares e equações cartesianas, implícitas e explícitas.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="pt_BR">
      Plots foi projetado para integrar-se bem com o ambiente GNOME e tirar proveito
      de hardware moderno usando OpenGL.
    </p>

  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.github.alexhuntley.Plots.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexhuntley/Plots/main/res/screenshot_fourier.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexhuntley/Plots/main/res/screenshot_polar_implicit.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alexhuntley/Plots/main/res/screenshot_dark_sliders.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/alexhuntley/Plots</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/alexhuntley/Plots/issues</url>
  <url type="translate">https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/plots/</url>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />

  <provides>
    <binary>plots</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.8.4" date="2022-09-30">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Improved copy &amp; paste compatibility with LaTeX and Unicode formulae</li>
          <li>New tooltip text on the toolbar buttons</li>
          <li>The formula editor now supports the Home and End keys</li>
          <li>Bug fixes</li>
          <li>Updated translations</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.3" date="2022-09-24">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Tweaked the color palette for graphs</li>
          <li>Dark mode now has a distinct color palette</li>
          <li>Bug fixes</li>
          <li>Updated translations</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.2" date="2022-09-23">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Bug fixes</li>
          <li>Updated translations</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.1" date="2022-09-21">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Bug fixes</li>
          <li>Updated translations</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="2022-09-20">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Port to GTK 4 and Libadwaita, for improved performance and a cleaner look</li>
          <li>Bug fixes</li>
          <li>Updated translations</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2022-09-18">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>New image export feature;</li>
          <li>New, more convenient color picker;</li>
          <li>Dark mode support;</li>
          <li>New settings window, allowing the line thickness and quality to be customized;</li>
          <li>Improved graphical accuracy;</li>
          <li>Bug fixes;</li>
          <li>Added Chinese (Simplified) translation;</li>
          <li>Updated existing translations.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.2" date="2022-04-04">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Bug fixes;</li>
          <li>Runtime and dependency updates;</li>
          <li>Added Croatian, Farsi, Spanish and Portuguese translations;</li>
          <li>Updated other translations.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.1" date="2021-09-21">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>New feature: implicit equations in x and y;</li>
          <li>Added Czech, Hungarian, Italian, Lithuanian, Norwegian and Turkish translations.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.0" date="2021-09-18">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for equations of the form x = f(y);</li>
          <li>Added support for polar equations of the forms r = f(θ) and θ = f(r);</li>
          <li>Added support for custom logarithm bases;</li>
          <li>Added animations to zooming;</li>
          <li>Refined the grid appearance, and added grid labels;</li>
          <li>Added French and Dutch translations;</li>
          <li>Minor bug fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.1" date="2021-01-28">
      <description>
        <p>Fix help missing in Flatpak</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.0" date="2021-01-25">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>UI and styling improvements;</li>
          <li>Added zoom in, out and reset buttons;</li>
          <li>Added sign/sgn and sinc functions;</li>
          <li>Miscellaneous bug fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.4" date="2021-01-24">
      <description>
        <p>Added floor and ceiling functions. Bugfixes and refactoring.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.3" date="2021-01-23">
      <description>
        <p>Various bugfixes and code improvements. Added missing cosech, asech, acsch, acosech and acoth functions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.2" date="2021-01-21">
      <description>
        <p>Added keyboard shortcuts for undo and redo</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.1" date="2021-01-21">
      <description>
        <p>New feature: undo/redo. Various bugfixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2021-01-19">
      <description>
        <p>New feature: cut, copy and paste of formulae!</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2021-01-18">
      <description>
        <p>New feature: variables and sliders. Easily modify the parameters
        in your equations with just a click!</p>
        <p>Also added a shortcut to select all the contents of a formula box,
        and updated the in-app documentation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2021-01-16">
      <description>
        <p>Improved the UI and added coloured graphs!</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.6" date="2021-01-14">
      <description>
        <p>UI improvements to formula editors:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Flatter delete button;</li>
          <li>Formula editing boxes can now scroll horizontally, and the formula pane now
          only scrolls vertically;</li>
          <li>Formulae scroll to the cursor position when it moves.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.5" date="2021-01-11">
      <description>
        <p>Added Help to menu, wrote manual pages describing available functions</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.4" date="2021-01-10">
      <description>
        <p>Fix superscript insertion on AZERTY keyboards</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.3" date="2021-01-09">
      <description>
        <p>Fix graph rendering on hidpi displays</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.2" date="2021-01-08">
      <description>
        <p>Fix AppStream data</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.1" date="2021-01-08">
      <description>
        <p>Remove sympy dependency</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2020-12-31">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release</p>
      </description>
    </release>

  </releases>
</component>
